Guide to the Women's Refugee Commission Records, 1979-2020; 1979-ongoing, bulk 1989-2011 RL.01405
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 28 boxes
  - Holly Myers Central American Delegation, 6 Mar. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Ethiopia Delegation Judy Mayotte, 13 Apr. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission Meeting chaired by Dawn Calabra, 13 Apr. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Ethiopia & Eritrea Narrative Part 2, 14 Apr. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Ethiopia Delegation Anne, 14 Apr. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Ethiopia Delegation: Mary Moran, 15 Apr. 1992 (Box 39)
  - Central American Delegation, 29 May 1992, 2 copies (Box 39)
  - Voices, 19 Jan. 1993 (Box 39)
  - Liv Ulman of the Women's Commission on Refugees, 8 Feb. 1993 (Box 39)
  - Dr. Pat Walker Cambodia, 1 July 1993 (Box 39)
  - Ann Gold Feld, Lelieu Brown Cambodia and Landmines, 25 July 1993 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission No. 2: Somalia- Nana Apadeau, Beverlee Bruce, 27 July 1993 (Box 39)
  - Judy Mayotte - Sudan and National Sovereignty, 28 July 1993 (Box 39)
  - Other Voices, 27 Sept. 1994 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission Amal Protrait, Maha Portrait, 7 Apr. 1997 (Box 39)
  - Annual Luncheon Honoring Outstanding Refugee Women, 15 May 1997 (Box 39)
  - Ref. Youth Leadership Training DC, Sept. 1997 (Box 39)
  - Rwanda Dancers, Transit Camp-Gisenyi, Exteriot prison, Sept. 1997 (Box 39)
  - RYLT DC, Sept. 1997 (Box 39)
  - Women's Commission No. 2 Gail Furman, Carmen Valeruma, Mary Diaz, 8 Apr. 1998 (Box 39)
  - Womens Commission No. 3 Mary Diaz (continued), Beverlee Bruce, Mary Anne Schwalbe, 8 Apr. 1998 (Box 39)
  - Meryl Streep, 24 Apr. 1998 (Box 39)
  - Portrait: Tserina Yangdon, Julie Nsanzurwimo interviews, 27 Apr. 1998 (Box 39)
  - 1999 Voices of Courage Awards (Raw Footage), 13 May 1999, 2 tapes (Box 39)
  - Burandi Bubanza, Oct. 2000 (Box 39)
  - A Child's Right: Education in Emergencies, June 2001 (Box 39, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0012, Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0010, Video-file RL01405-VHS-0012.mov)
  - Maha Muna Pakistan tape 2, Dec. 2001 (Box 39)
  - Sierra Leone, 12 Apr. 2002 (Box 39)
  - Mission to Chad (Tape 4- Window Dub), 26 Jan. 2005 (Box 39)
  - Mission to Chad 1/05 B Roll Pkg, 14 Feb. 2005 (Box 39)
  - Mission to Chad: Short Film- Final Cut, 12 Jan. 2006 (Box 39)
  - Disabilities Report Launch, 23 June 2008 (Box 39)
  - Voices of Courage Awards Luncheon, 7 May 2009 (Box 39)
  - Mary Anne Schwalbe, undated (Box 39)
  - Rwanda No. 3 Nyamata, undated (Box 39)
  - Uganda Tape No. 5, undated (Box 39)
  - Uganda Tape No. 6 (North Uganda), undated (Box 39)
  - No. 2, undated (Box 39)
  - Cambodia Delegation 4, undated (Box 39)
  - Cambodia Delegation 6, undated (Box 39)
  - Cambodia Delegation 7, undated (Box 39)
  - Maryanne's Discourse Tape1-3, undated (Box 39)
  - Sierra Leone No. 4, undated (Box 39)
  - The Least of These: Family Detention in America, undated (Box 39)
  - WRC 20th Anniversary Video, undated (Box 39)
  - Liv Ullmann Acceptance Speech, 1999 Voice of Courage Awards, 1999 (Box 40)
  - Women's Commission Retreat Tape No. 1, 21 Sept. 1999 (Box 40)
  - Dr. Pat Walker, Nov. 1991 (Box 40)
  - Maryanne Schwalbe, 9 Nov. 1991 (Box 40)
  - Sima Wali Part 3, 18 Nov. 1991 (Box 40)
  - IRC Sign and Nana Apadeau, 20 Nov. 1991 (Box 40)
  - WCRWC luncheon, 28 Jan. 1992 (Box 40)
  - Holly Myers Central American Delegation, 6 Mar. 1992 (Box 40)
  - Central American Delegation, 29 May 1992 (Box 40)
  - Ethiopia Eritrea Delegation, 29 May 1992 (Box 40)
  - Judy Mayotte, Sudan and Children, 15 July 1993 (Box 40)
  - Ref Youth Leadership Training DC 4, Sept. 1997 (Box 40)
  - Refugee Youth Leadership Training DC 1, Sept. 1997 (Box 40)
  - Afghanistan Mary MacMackin Parsa, 12 Oct. 1999, 2 tapes (Box 40)
  - Ayuba-Liberia, Nadia-Afghanistan, Bengalee-Guinea, 17 Apr. 2001 (Box 40)
  - Mary Diaz Interview, 17 Apr. 2001 (Box 40)
  - Winifred Barbu, Mary Diaz Interview, 17 Apr. 2001 (Box 40)
  - Crisis In Afghanistan, Naomi Wolf, Nov. 2001 (Box 40)
  - Zona Stills XFER, 14 Feb. 2002 (Box 40)
  - Safety-Luncheon, May 2002 (Box 40)
  - Aster Interview, Group Meeting, 15 Apr. 2003 (Box 40)
  - Elizabeth Detention Facility, Ermias Interview, 15 Apr. 2003 (Box 40)
  - Jean Pierre Intv, Aster Office B-roll, 15 Apr. 2003 (Box 40)
  - Wackenhut Broll, Wendy Intru 5, 16 Apr. 2003 (Box 40)
  - Wackenhut Broll, Wendy Intru 6, 16 Apr. 2003 (Box 40)
  - A tribute to Mary Diaz, Oct. 2003 (Box 40)
  - Linda Hartke, undated (Box 40)
  - No. 1, undated (Box 40)
  - Cambodia Delegation 3, undated (Box 40)
  - Dr. Anne G Plus Sina Bieu Part 2, undated (Box 40)
  - Latin American Delegation, undated (Box 40)
  - Refugee Youth Chat 1, undated (Box 40)
  - Refugee Youth Chat 2, undated (Box 40)
  - Refugee Youth Chat 4, undated (Box 40)
  - Women in Detention, undated (Box 40)
  - Danane-Beverlee Bruce, Mary Anne Schwalle (Box 40)
  - Ethiopia Delegation: Asmara Street Children, Mary Moran, undated (Box 40)
  - No label, undated, 4 tapes (Box 40)
  - 1999 Voices of Courage Awards, 1999 (Box 41)
  - Malawi Mului Hill, Aug. 1989 (Box 41)
  - Footage from delegation to Cote D'Ivoire, Guinea, and Liberia, 25 Apr. 1991 (Box 41)
  - Ethiopian and Eritrean Delegation, 29 May 1992 (Box 41)
  - Central American Delegation, 29 May 1992 (Box 41)
  - Liv Ullman Post-Symposium Statements, 10 June 1992 (Box 41)
  - CBS Up to the Minute, 9 Oct. 1992 (Box 41)
  - Rwanda Women's Commission, Sept. 1997 (Box 41)
  - Luncheon Video Rough Cut, 28 Apr. 1998 (Box 41)
  - April 1999 in Albania (Box 41)
  - The Crisis Inside Kosovo, 20 Apr. 1999 (Box 41)
  - Hillary Clinton Remarks for WCRWC, 10 May 1999 (Box 41)
  - Luncheon, June 2000 (Box 41)
  - Voices of Courage Refugee Youth Speakout, June 2000 (Box 41)
  - Refugee Women and Peace, May 2002 (Box 41)
  - Mary Diaz: A Decade of Leadership, 17 Oct. 2003 (Box 41)
  - Mission to Chad, 26 Jan. 2005 (Box 41)
  - Fending for Themselves: Pakistan, undated (Box 41)
  - Repatriation Symposium: Going Home, undated (Box 41)
  - The Refugee Experience, undated (Box 41)
  - Urban Refugees video, 2011 (Box 49)
  - Voices of Courage luncheon, 2011 (Box 49)
  - Women's Refugee Commission general organization video, 2011 (Box 49)
  - WC Mission to Chad 1A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0001)
  - WC Mission to Chad 1B Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0002)
  - WC Mission to Chad 2A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0003)
  - WC Mission to Chad 3A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0004)
  - WC Mission to Chad 4A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0005)
  - WC Mission to Chad 5A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0006)
  - WC Mission to Chad 5B Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0007)
  - WC Mission to Chad 6A Masters of Field Tapes, January 2005 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0008)
  - WC Mission to Chad 1/2005 2B/3B Masters of Field Tapes (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0009)
  - Women's Commission 6 spots tied, 30 March 1998 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0010)
  - Voices, 10 March 1998 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0011)
  - Other Voices, 10 March 1998 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0012)
  - The Refugee Experience, 19 March 1998 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0013)
  - Portraits, Edited Master, 13 November 1998 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0014)
  - 1999 Voices of Courage Awards, 4 short films for event playback (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0015)
  - Voices of Courage: Refugee Youth Speak Out, Master, 1 June 2000 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0016)
  - A Tribute to Mary Diaz, Master, 23 April 2004 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-BCAM-0017)
  - Mary Diaz, Morning News Channel 4, 7 March 1999 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0001)
  - Voices of Courage: Refugee Youth Speak Out, June 2000 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0002)
  - A Child's Right: Education in Emergencies, June 2001 (Box 77, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0003)
  - Voices, March 1994 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0004)
  - Albania, undated (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-VHS-0005)
  - Mission to Chad, final cut, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0001)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T1, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0002)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T2, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0003)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T3, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0004)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T4, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0005)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T5, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0006)
  - Mission to Chad, Field Tapes, T6, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-DVCAM-0007)
  - Education report/ Tribute to Mary Diaz/ Cathy O'Neill Show, undated (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0001)
  - Liv Ullmann, 23 September 2009? (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0002)
  - WRC Staff 5, undated (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0003)
  - WRC Staff 2, undated (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0004)
  - WRC Videos, Masters, All versions, 19 December 2008 (Box 78, Video-cassette RL01405-MDV-0005)
  - What Happens When I Go to Immigration Court?, undated (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0001)
  - Youth Zones: Voices from Emergencies, 2010 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0002)
  - Carolyn Makinson Archives, undated (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0003)
  - WRC Disability, 2013 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0004)
  - Urban Refugees: The Right to Live in Dignity, September 2011 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0005)
  - Mission to Chad, January 2005 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0006)
  - WRC 25 Years, Lower Res for Web, 18 April 2014 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0007)
  - WRC 25 Years, High Res No Credits, 18 April 2014 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0008)
  - WRC 25 Years, High Res with Credits, 18 April 2014 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0009)
  - Liv Ullmann PSAs, 28 September 2006 (Box 78, Video-disc RL01405-DVD-0010)
  - Pippa Scott Voice Over Latin Am. Delegation, undated (Box 78, Audio-cassette RL01405-CS-0001)
  - Photographs, Slides, and Negatives
    - Slides
      - P. Scott-Women's Commission meeting photographs, Fall 1991 and Fall 1992 (Box 5)
      - Shania Suleman (Afghanistan) (Box 5)
      - ORR Conference (Box 5)
    - Tanzania, 1998-2001 (Box 61)
    - Zambia, 2001 RHR Delegation (Box 61)
    - Sinje Camp, Liberia Reproductive Health Group, undated (Box 61)
    - Mexico and Guatemala, January 1998 (Box 61)
    - Thailand, October 1997 (Box 61)
    - Angola, February 2001 (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - Southeast Asia, 1996 and undated (Box 61)
    - Angola, 1996-2001 and undated (Box 61)
    - Lebanon, September 1997 (Box 62)
    - General RHR Slides, 1996 and undated (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova: Shqipe Malushi, May-June 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova: Shkoder Camp, May 1999 (2 folders) (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova: Kavaje, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova: Maternity & Mental Health Hospitals, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova:May 29th Conference, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova: Italian Camp, Durres, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania/Kosova:Tirana Stadium, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Delegation to Albania, April 1999 (Box 62)
    - Albania, May 1999 (Box 62)
    - Bosnia, July 2001 (Box 62)
    - Africa, 1992-1998 and undated (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - Rwanda--Catherine O'Neill, January 1995 (Box 63)
    - Delegation to Macedonia, 1999 (Box 63)
    - Afghanistan & Pakistan, 1998-2002 (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - Afghanistan photographs, 2001-2002; 13 digital files extracted from a 3.5-inch floppy disk; approximately 509 kilobytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0002, Disk RL01405-FL3-0002)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes thirteen color photographs, jpeg file format.
    - Rwanda, undated (Box 64)
    - Haiti, August 2002 (Box 64)
    - Columbia: ANMUCIC [Asociacion Nacional de Mujeres Campesinas, Indienas y Negras de Columbia] and Drawings, January 1999 (Box 64)
    - Kosovo, 9/1999 (Box 64)
    - East Timor, November 1999 (Box 64)
    - Ethiopia & Eritrea, March 2001 (Box 64)
    - Azerbaijan, 1994 (Box 64)
    - Cairo Delegation, September 2004 (Box 64)
    - Lebanon, 2000 (Box 64)
    - Knitting Project: Bosnia & Croatia, 1994 (Box 64)
    - Liberia, 2004 and undated (Box 64)
    - Liberia, December 2005 (Box 64)
    - Liberia Photographs, 2004; 25 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 44 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0009, Disk RL01405-OP-0013)
      Includes twenty-five photographs, 20 in color; some with black-and-white copies, jpeg file format.
    - Liberia Photographs, 2005; 54 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 15 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0009, Disk RL01405-OP-0014)
      Includes forty-six color photographs. Copyright Carolyn Makinson, except for last 6: copyright Lori Heninger. Jpeg file format.
    - Lebanon, 1997-1999 (Box 64)
    - Columbia, November-December 1998 (Box 65)
    - Central America: Guatemala, 1992-1998 and undated (Box 65)
    - Cambodia, 1993-1994 and undated (Box 65)
    - Burundi Delegation, October 2010 (Box 65)
    - Burundi/Tanzania, February 1998 (Box 65)
    - Bhutanese Refugees in Nepal, July 1998 (Box 65)
    - Azerbaijan, Feb, 2001 (Box 65)
    - Azerbaijan, Baku photographs, 2001; 25 digital files extracted from an optical disk; approximately 8 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0003, Disk RL01405-OP-0001)
      Includes twenty-five color photographs, jpeg file format.
    - Azerbaijan IRC/R/Camp photographs, 2001; 37 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 13 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0003, Disk RL01405-OP-0002)
      Includes thirty-seven color photographs, jpeg file format.
    - Azerbaijan photographs, 2001; 36 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 12 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0003, Disk RL01405-OP-0003)
      Includes thirty-six color photographs, jpeg file format.
    - Azerbaijan, Baku photographs, 2001; 24 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 7 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0003, Disk RL01405-OP-0004)
      Includes twenty-four color photographs, jpeg file format.
    - Azerbaijan, Baku, ECHO/German Camp, 2001; 25 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 7 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0003, Disk RL01405-OP-0005)
    - Tanzania, 1998-2000 (Box 66)
    - Sudan, 1998-1999 (Box 66)
    - Thai-Burma Border, 2000 (Box 66)
    - Sierra Leone: Planes, Equipment, & Delegation Members, 2002 (Box 66)
    - Sierra Leone: Scenery, 2002 April (Box 66)
    - Sierra Leone: Housing, 2002 April (Box 66)
    - Sierra Leone: Misc, 2002 April (Box 66)
    - Sierra Leone Photos, 2002 (Box 66)
    - Guinea & Sierra Leone, 2000-2002 and undated (Box 66)
    - Serbia & Montenegro, 2000 August ( 2 folders) (Box 67)
    - Rwanda, 2000 (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - Sierra Leone, 2002 October (Box 67)
    - Sierra Leone Elections, May 2002 (Box 67)
    - Sierra Leone, 2002 (Box 67)
    - Save the Children Fund Photos, 1995-1999 (Box 67)
    - Sierra Leone, March 1997 (Box 67)
    - West Bank and Gaza, 2002 February (Box 68)
    - RHR: Thai-Burma Border, Cambodia, 1994-1996 and undated (Box 68)
    - RH: Thailand, 1997 (2 folders) (Box 68)
    - Vietnamese Refugees in Hong Kong, 1990 (Box 68)
    - Sexual Violence, Central Park Boathouse, 1997 (Box 68)
    - Zambia, 2001 (Box 68)
    - Sierra Leone, 2003 May (Box 68)
    - Sierra Leone, 2002 October (Box 68)
    - Former Yugoslavia, 1994-1999 (Box 68)
    - Azerbaijan, 1998 (Box 69)
    - Adolescent Report, undated (Box 69)
    - Photo Loans, 1995-2000 (Box 69)
    - Student Projects, 1995-1999 (Box 69)
    - Photos for Newsletter, 1995 (Box 69)
    - Liv Ullmann, undated (Box 69)
    - Children & Adolescents Photos Used in Reports, undated (Box 69)
    - WCRWC/BNS Presentation, June 2004 (Box 69)
    - Children Youth Asylum Projects, El Paso, Texas, Facilities, June 1998 (Box 69)
    - U.S. Detention Photos, 1996-2000 and undated (Box 69)
    - Women Refugees, 1980-1994 and undated (2 folders) (Box 69)
    - Untitled, 1999-2000 and undated (Box 70)
    - Susan Stark Alberts, undated (Box 70)
    - Mary Diaz, 1998-2002 (Box 70)
    - Beverlee Bruce, 1996-1997 (Box 70)
    - Children of War, Children of Hope, 1998-1999 and undated (Box 70)
    - Children of War, Children of Hope D.C. Reception, 12/1998, 7/1999 (Box 70)
    - Thai/Burma, 1999-2000 (Box 70)
    - Children of War, Children of Hope, 1999 and undated (Box 71)
    - Phyllis Oakley honor, February 28, 1997 (Box 71)
    - Liv Ullmann Book Signing, February 24, 2000 (Box 71)
    - Mary Anne Schwalbe: Misc., 1995-2002 and undated (Box 71)
    - Uganda/Sudanese Adolescents, 2001 and undated (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Untitled, 2010 (Box 72)
    - For Scanning & CD Burning, 2002 (Box 72)
    - Necessary Targets photos and slides, 10/1996 (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Repro Health, Thailand, 10/1997 (Box 72)
    - Thailand Karenni Camp, Kampng Chhnay, Cambodia, 2/9/1994 (Box 72)
    - World Refugee Day, 2001 (Box 72)
    - From UN Photo Library, All in refugee/IDP settings, undated (Box 73)
    - UNHCR Refugee women's Consultation, 6/2001 (Box 73)
    - Global Refugee Women's Consultation, June 20-22, 2001 (Box 73)
    - UNHCR- Ref. Womens Consultation, 6/2001 (Box 73)
    - Luncheon Photos, Invite, 2002 (Box 73)
    - UNDP slides, undated (Box 73)
    - 1999 Calendar (Box 73)
    - Commission on the Status of Women, 3/2001 (Box 73)
    - CSW meeting dialog, copyright Melanie?, undated (Box 73)
    - Daytona Conference, 11/ 1998 (Box 73)
    - Congressional Hearing on Children in Detention (Angelina Jolie), 2003 (Box 73)
    - Landmines Awareness Tour, May 1996 (Box 73)
    - RHRC [Reproductive Health for Refugees?] Forum, 12/1998 (Box 73)
    - WCRWC Reception @ Swedish Ambassador's Residence, Washington, D.C., March 12, 2002 (Box 73)
    - WCRWC Board Meeting/Advocacy Day 3/1999 (Box 74)
    - Liv Ullmann material, 1990-1998 and undated (Box 74)
    - Catherine O'Neill material, 1995-2001 and undated (Box 74)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 74)
    - UNHCR photos, 1979-1998 and undated (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - UN Special Session on Children, May 2002 (Box 74)
    - Refugee Children, 1993-1999 and undated (Box 74)
    - Children eating, water supply, 1987-1993 (Box 74)
    - Children, Education, 1980-1990 (Box 74)
    - Children, Singles (focus on one child), 1986-1994 (Box 74)
    - Necessary Targets Photos, 10/1996 (Box 75)
    - Children of War, 1995-1998 (Box 75)
    - Annual Meeting, c. 2000 (Box 75)
    - Annual Report photos used, 2002 (Box 75)
    - AWID [Association for Women's Rights in Development] Forum, 1996 (Box 75)
    - Beijing Conference, Photos Melanie Wyler, June & JUly 1993 (Box 75)
    - Beijing/NGO Forum, Aug/Sept 1995 (Box 75)
    - Beijing + 5, 6/2000 (Box 75)
    - Bellagio Photos, 1/1997 (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - 15 Anniv. book photos, 1987-2004 (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - WRC General, 1982-1994 (Box 76)
    - WRC Misc. Photos, 1996-2003 and undated (Box 76)
    - Women's Commission General, 1992-2003 and undated (3 folders) (Box 76)
    - Women's Commission File Folders/Photos, 1996 and undated (Box 56)
    - Photograph Album [by Refugees?], undated (Box 56)
    - Oversize photographs (Oversize-folder 1)
    - UNAIDS Photograph Library photo, 2001; 35 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 9 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0008, Disk RL01405-OP-0008)
      Includes converted photocard, jpeg file format.
    - Africa and Croatian refugees, undated; 2 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 94 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0008, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0002)
      Includes two black-and-white photographs, tiff file format.
    - UNHCR photograph, 2000; 1 digital file extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 66 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0008, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0008)
      One black-and-white UNHCR photograph, tiff file format.
    - Photographs, 2000; 2 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 86 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0008, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0010)
      Includes one color and one black-and-white photograph, untitled. Tiff file format.
- Printed Materials and Publications Series, 8 boxes
  The Reports series consists largely of the publications and documentation produced by the Women's Refugee Commission staff about refugee conditions in crisis situations around the world. Trip reports constitute a large portion within the series, covering visits to refugee camps in Africa, Asia, Europe, and South America, as well as United States prisons (where asylum-seekers are detained). Also included are public reports and guidelines on issues like domestic and gender-based violence; reproductive health and the Minimum Initial Service Package (MISP); armed conflict and its effects on children; and fuel alternatives and strategies. Drafts of publications, newsletters from the WRC, and a small amount of drawings by refugee children make up the rest of this series.
  Box 49 of this series is from Accession 2010-0150. Boxes 59 and 60 of this series are from Accession 2016-0110.
  Arrangement note
  Folders may include multiple versions of a report, each in a different language. Also, folder titles frequently reflect the subject, location, and date, instead of the full title of each report.
  Conditions Governing Access
  - Gender-based Violence Tools Manual (Box 6)
  - Afghan Women and Children, December 2001 (Box 6)
  - Refugee and Internally Displaced Women and Children in Serbia and Montenegro, September 2001 (Box 6)
  - Participatory Research Study with Adolescents in Northern Uganda, 2001 (Box 6)
  - INS Moves Refugee Women from Krome to Turner Guilford Knight Correctional Center, Miami, June 2001 (Box 6)
  - You Cannot Dane if You Cannot Stand: Rwanda, April 2001 (Box 6)
  - Millones No Vistos, Colombia, March 2002 (Box 6)
  - Trip reports: Thailand, Lenanon, Tanzania, June 1999 (Box 6)
  - Trip reports: Angola, Mozambique, Bosnia, Croatia, Serbia, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Trip reports: Asylum-seekers in U.S. prisons, Tanzania, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Reports: Afghanistan, Rwanda, Iranian refugees in Turkey, 1996-2000 (Box 6)
  - Reports: Burmese refugees in Bangkok, 2000; Colombia, 2003; Iraqi civilians in Iraq and Jordan, February 2003 (Box 6)
  - Field reports: Rwanda, Burundi, Guatemala, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Reproductive health: Palestinian refugees in Lebanon, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Reproductive health among Burmese refugees in Thailand, December 1997 (Box 6)
  - Reports: Asylum-seekers in the U.S., 1997; Assistance to women in Kabul, Afghanistan, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Children in Sierra Leone and Rwanda, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Women and adolescents in the Caucasus (Azerbaijan, Armenia, etc.), 1998 (Box 6)
  - Domestic violence in Lebanon, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Reproductive healthcare: Sudanese refugees in Chad, August 2004 (Box 6)
  - Reports: Krome Detention Center abuse, Burundi, Colombia, October 2000 (Box 6)
  - Kosovo, reproductive health in Tanzania, and violence against Tibetan women, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Gender audit of reconstruction programmes in Southeast Europe, July 2000 (Box 6)
  - Beijing Platform for Action; Global Survey of Education in Emergencies (Box 6)
  - Gender dimensions of internal displacement, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Guidelines on protecting refugee women; reproductive health for youth; emergency obstetric care (Box 6)
  - Livelihood opportunities, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
  - Education in Emergencies, 2006 (Box 7)